As long as modern-day crimes involve people,
طالما جرائم العصر الحديث تتضمّن بشراً
there are no unsolvable mysteries!
!لا توجد ألغاز لا تُحلّ
The stage today is a first-class hotel!
مسرح اليوم أحد الفنادق الراقية
I found the mysterious organization!
!وجدتُ المنظمة الغامضة
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ دماغه لبالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
The Game Company Murder Case
جريمة قتل شركة الألعاب
Baker Hotel
أشرف العمّ على لعبة؟
Your dad supervised a game?
فندق بيكا
That's right!
صحيح
It's titled, "Detective Kogoro Mori's House of Reasoning!"
تُسمى "منزل استنتاج المتحرّي "العظيم موري كوغورو
The player encounters a dead body in a mysterious mansion,
يجد اللاعب جثّة في قصر غامض
and gets hints from Detective Mori who just happens to be there
ويتلقى تلميحات من المتحرّي موري الذي يلتقيه صدفةً
to solve the case!
ويحلّ القضيّة
That's practically the pattern with me every time...
...هذا السيناريو معي كلّ مرة تقريباً
But is it okay for their guest to be like that?
لكن هل سيجري الأمر على ما يرام وضيف شرفهم بهذا الحال؟
This is what you get for drinking so much last night
هذا ما تناله لإفراطك في الشرب البارحة
for your "pre-celebration"!
!"في حفلتك "السابقة للحفلة
I only had five or six drinks...
...شربت 5 أو 6 كؤوس فحسب
Gin, vodka, bourbon...
...جين، فودكا، بوربون
Gin and Vodka...
...جين وفودكا
Those are the codenames for the men in black
إنّهما الاسمان الرمزيّان للرجلان بالرداء الأسود
who shrunk me!
!اللذان قلّصا جسدي
What long lines!
!يا للطابور الطويل
Of course they are!
لا عجب
Almost everyone in the gaming industry is here!
مُعظم العاملين في مجال صناعة الألعاب متواجدون هنا
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
It's me! Nakajima from Mantendo!
إنّه أنا، ناكاجيما من مانتيندو
I planned "Detective Kogoro Mori's House of Reasoning!"
خطّطتُ لعبة "منزل استنتاج المتحرّي "العظيم موري كوغورو
Thanks to you, we've produced an amazing game!
!أنتجنا لعبةً مذهلة بفضلك
You definitely excel at your work, Nakajima.
أنت تجيد عملك حقاً يا ناكاجيما
Assuming you really did plan that game.
بافتراض أنّك خططت لتلك اللعبة حقاً
Ueda!
!أويدا
I shouldn't have told you that the game would do well
كان عليّ ألّا أخبرك أنّ اللعبة ستلقى نجاحاً
if we used Detective Mori.
إذا استعملنا المتحرّي موري
Three days later, your proposal just happened to highlight that idea,
بعد ثلاثة أيام ترأسّت الفكرة عرضك التقديمي
and voila, here you are.
ومرت الأحداث وها نحن في إعلان اللعبة
You're a genius at stealing people's things!
أنت عبقريّ في سرقة حاجات الآخرين
Work, women...
...العمل، والنساء
Isn't that right, Takeshita?
صحيح يا تاكيشيتا؟
Yeah...
...أ-أجل
But that was back in college. It's in the past.
لكن كان ذلك أيام الجامعة، فنسيتُ الأمر
Well, I'll overlook it this time.
حسناً، سأتغاضى عن الأمر هذه المرّة
After all, you seem to be in trouble with the debt-collectors and all.
فيبدو أنّك في مشكلة مع محصّلي الديون وما شابه
Here's the number tag for your luggage!
هذه بطاقة رقم أمتعتك
96.
ستّ وتسعون
Hey, we're really late!
!تأخّر بنا الوقت
What?!
!ماذا؟
We need to hurry to the show floor and get things ready!
!علينا الإسراع لطابق العرض والتجهّز
Check this in first!
!سجّلوا هذه عندكم أوّلاً
Mine too!
!وحقيبتي
Hey, don't cut in line!
!لا تقطعا الصفّ
You should hurry too, you know!
!يجدر بك الإسراع أيضاً
The president will yell at you if you're late!
!سيوبّخك الرئيس إن تأخرت
You have a point...
...مـ-معك حق
Please try not to mix ours up.
لا تخلطوا بينها من فضلكم
All three of you have the same briefcase!
تحملون جميعاً نفس الحقيبة
Yes. And it's not just our briefcases--
...أجل، ليس حقائبنا فحسب
...our necktie pins and wristwatches too.
ينطبق الأمر على دبابيس ربطات عنقنا وساعات أيدينا
It's was the company president's idea
كانت فكرة رئيس الشركة
to give ordinary people an impression of our company.
بأن نعطي عامة الناس انطباعاً عن شركتنا
But in actuality, the briefcases are way too big and heavy.
لكنّ الحقائب كبيرة وثقيلة في الواقع
We brought them today,
أحضرناها معنا اليوم
but almost everyone in the company has left them here.
لكنّ معظم موظّفي الشركة أودعوها هنا
The president's probably the only guy lugging one around!
الرئيس وحده من يمشي بحقيبته الآن غالباً
Well, excuse me.
اعذروني على ذلك
Sir!
!حـ-حضرة الرئيس
Get to your posts!
!إلى أماكنكم فوراً
Yes! Right away!
!حـ-حاضر
Despicable...
...يا إلهي
Here's your number tag!
هذه بطاقتكم
Thanks!
شكراً
How lucky!
!يا لحظّي
Look, Conan-kun! Our tag number is 100 exactly!
!انظر يا كونان-كن، الرقم على بطاقتنا 100
Maybe today's our lucky day!
!ربما سيحصل أمرٌ حسن اليوم
She's easily excited...
...إنها تتحمّس بسرعة
Ahh! Stop!
!توقّف
How do you like this?!
!كيف هذه؟
I did it! I came from behind to win!
!فعلتُها! قلبت الطاولة
Great job, Ran-chan!
!مذهل يا ران-تشان
Very few people can pull that move off!
قلّ من يستطيع تنفيذ تلك الضربة
Eh? Really?!
ماذا؟ حقّاً؟
She might be lucky, after all...
...ربما الحظّ يحالفها بالفعل
So close! It really lights up if you get over 250...
كنت قريباً! يصدر ضوء لامع ...عندما تتجاوز 250
Hey, Nakajima!
!ناكاجيما
Will you come give this a try?
هلّا جربتِ هذه؟
Sure.
حسناً
It looks like Nakajima-san's going to try!
يبدو أنّ ناكاجيما-سان سيجرّب
Wow! Have you ever practiced anything?
مُذهل! أكنت تتمرّن على شيء في الماضي؟
A little boxing during my college days.
مارست القليل من الملاكمة في أيام الجامعة
Why don't you give it a shot, Ran-san?
ما رأيك بأن تجرّبي يا ران-سان؟
No, that's okay...
...كلا، لا داعي
It's a good stress-reliever!
هذا مُفيد في التخلّص من التوتر
Stress?
التوتر؟
Get back here now, Shinichi!
!ارجع بسرعة يا شينتشي
Want to try, Conan-kun?
تريد أن تجرّب يا كونان-كن؟
I need to use the bathroom!
!عليّ الذهاب لدورة المياه
Then let's go together, little boy.
لنذهب معاً إذاً يا فتى
I believe the restrooms are--
...أظنّ دورة المياه كانت
He's huge!
!رجل عملاق
Does he work at the game company too?
أيعمل في شركة ألعاب أيضاً؟
I don't know. I've never seen him before.
لا أدري، لم يسبق ورأيته
All three of you were in the same boxing club during college?
كنتم الثلاثة في نفس نادي الملاكمة في الجامعة؟
Yeah.
أجل
Until he quit halfway through, anyway.
حتّى انسحب في منتصف الطريق بالطبع
Ueda...
...أويدا
But to think we would all wind up in the same company...
من كان ليخطر له أنّنا سنعمل جميعاً في نفس الشركة
Number 98.
رقم 98
That's the logo for Nakajima-san's company.
هذا شعار شركة ناكاجيما-سان
Thank you!
شكراً
But that's strange.
لكن هذا غريب
He should have the company's necktie pin if he's an employee...
يُفترض أن يرتدي دبّوس ربطة العنق إن كان أحد الموظّفين
Anyway, I should buy the old man
...بعيداً عن ذلك، عليّ أن أشتري
some tomato juice for his hangover...
عصير طماطم للعمّ كي يتجاوز أثر الشراب
It's me, Tequila.
إنّها أنا، تيكيلا
The deal's done.
تمّت الصفقة
Don't worry, Vodka.
لا تقلق يا فودكا
Pass the word on to Gin.
انقل الأمر لجين
This guy's one of the men in black!
!إنّه... أحد أفراد منظمة الرداء الأسود
Just a kid. He dropped some change.
مجرّد صبيّ، أسقط عملاته
I finally found you!
!وجدتكم أخيراً
Hey, Mister! Could you move your leg?
هلّا حرّكت رجلك يا عمّ؟
I can't get my 10-yen coin...
...لا أستطيع أخذ عملة العشر ينّات خاصتي
Don't touch me, boy!
!لا تلمسني أيّها الصبيّ العفن
Alright!
!حسنٌ
I stuck a hidden microphone and transmitter onto his shoe sole!
!ألصقتُ لاقطاً وقطعة إرسال تحت حذائه
He'll lead me to the others!
...سيقودني الآن
To Gin and Vodka!
!جين وفودكا
Huh? It won't open...
...ماذا؟ لا يفتح
A door?
باب؟
A restroom stall?
حجرة حمّام؟
Wait! Little boy!
!انتظر! أيّها الفتى
That big man was wearing this shoe!
إنّه... الحذاء الذي كان !يرتديه الرجل العملاق
He was in the explosion!
!أصابه الانفجار
Little boy! It's dangerous here!
!المكان خطر هنا يا فتى
Hurry outside!
!اخرج بسرعة
I had finally found a clue leading to them!
بعدما... بعدما أمسكتُ بخيط !يقودني لهما أخيراً
Why did this have to happen?!
!لمَ حصل هذا؟
A terrorist attack?
هجوم إرهابيّ؟
My guess is that the explosives were attached
أظنّ أنّه كانت هناك متفجرات مزروعة
to the toilet or something else.
في الحمّام أو ما شابه
A random murder...
جريمة قتل عشوائية إذاً؟
There was one victim.
الضحيّة شخص واحد فحسب
Any idea who it was?
أتعرفون من يكون؟
All that's left are shreds...
...تبقّت أشلاء فحسب
Did any of you see anybody suspicious?
إذاً، أرأى أحدكم شخصاً مثيراً للشبهة؟
No...
...كـ-كلا
Not really...
لا أحد بالتحديد
I did!
!أنا رأيت
I saw the guy who died!
رأيت الشخص الذي مات
You did, Conan-kun?!
!حـ-حقاً يا كونان-كن؟
He was a really big man!
!كان رجلاً عملاقاً
He might have been from western Japan...
...ربما من منطقة كانساي
You saw him too, Nakajima-san!
!رأيته أيضاً يا ناكاجيما-سان
The big man in black clothes we bumped into in the lobby!
الشخص العملاق بالرداء الأسود الذي !ارتطمنا به في الردهة
How do you know he was from western Japan?
كيف عرفت أنّه من كانساي؟
I heard his accent in the bathroom right before he died:
سمعتُ لكنته في الحمّام قبيل موته
"Huh? It won't open. Is this empty?"
"ماذا؟ لا يفتح. لحظة، مفتوحة بالفعل؟"
He must've been talking about a restroom stall!
!كان يقصد حجرة حمّام بالتأكيد
In that case, the explosives must have been set near the stall door.
في تلك الحالة، لا بدّ أنّ المتفجرات كانت قرب باب الحجرة
Excuse me...
المعذرة، أيمكنني الكلام؟
Company president!
!حـ-حضرة الرئيس
President?
الرئيس؟
Yes. I'm Mantendo's president, Ishikawa.
أجل، أنا رئيس مانتيندو، إيشيكاوا
I actually received a strange letter three days ago.
تلقّيتُ رسالةً غريبة قبل 3 أيام
A strange letter...
رسالة غريبة؟
"Cancel the show or else." This is a threat letter!
!إ-إنّها رسالة تهديد
Why didn't you contact the police the minute you received this?!
!لمَ لم تتصل بالشرطة عند تلقيك لها؟
I apologize. I thought it was an ordinary harassment letter.
آسف، ظننتُها مجرّد مضايقة عاديّة
Inspector. We found this in the debris.
حضرة المفتّش، وجدنا هذه في الحطام
The key makes sense, but what's this round thing?
أفهم المفتاح، لكن ما هذا الشيء المستدير؟
That's my company's emblem.
إنّه شعار شركتي
Come to think of it, that big man had one of those briefcases.
بالمناسبة، كان يحمل ذاك الرجل العملاق حقيبة كهذه
But why did he have it?
لكن لمَ ذلك؟
He took it from the baggage counter, but...
...أخذها من مكتب إيداع الحقائب، لكن
What tremendous power! It bent this piece of iron!
!يا للقوّة الهائلة، ثنت قطعة حديدة كهذه
What?!
!ماذا؟
There's something strange about that emblem!
!هناك أمرٌ غريب بهذا الشعار
Why is it bent away from the briefcase?!
لمَ مثنيّ باتّجاه معاكس للحقيبة؟
If the explosion happened outside the case,
...إذا وقع الانفجار خارج الحقيبة
it should be bent inward!
!يُفترض أنّه ثُني للداخل
This was no terrorist attack! It was a murder!
!لم يكن هذا هجوماً إرهابياً! بل جريمة قتل
Somebody wanted that man dead!
كان هناك من يستهدف !موت ذاك الرجل
Yes. The bomber is the one who gave him the briefcase!
أجل، المُفجّر هو الشخص الذي أعطاه تلك الحقيبة
The deal probably took place there--
...يُفترض أنّ الصفقة جرت هناك
--the best place to make an exchange without arousing suspicion
أفضل مكان للمقايضة دون إثارة الشبهة
by switching number tags!
!بتبديل بطاقات الأرقام
The baggage counter!
!مكتب الإيداع
No, nobody else has claimed their things except for that large man...
كلا، لم يطلب أحد أمتعته باستثناء ذاك الرجل العملاق
Which means that the other person hasn't come to claim the other bag!
ما يعني أنّ الشخص الآخر !لم يأت لأخذ حقيبته بعد
Great!
حسنٌ
There still might be clues leading to Gin and Vodka!
لم تختف تماماً... الدلائل التي !تقودني لجين وفودكا، الرجلان بالرداء الأسود
Where do you think you're going?
أين تذهب؟
I need to see the Inspector!
!عليّ رؤية المفتّش
No way. He's busy right now.
لا يمكن، إنّه مشغول الآن
Let me go before the bomber gets away!
!دعني! علينا الإسراع وإلّا سيفلت الفاعل
If that happens, then their--
...عندها سيتحقق
Ran...
...ران-نيتشان
Where were you?!
!أين كنت؟
You're hurt...
...أنت مصاب
What on earth happened?
ماذا حصل؟
100 and 96...
...مئة وستّ وتسعون
Those are the number tags for our things at the baggage counter.
إنّها بطاقات أرقام حقائبنا
100 is mine, and 96 is Dad's.
مئة لي، وستّ وتسعون لأبي
He's still not doing well, so I'm holding his for him.
لا يزال متوعكاً، لذا أحتفظ ببطاقته
If I remember right, that man's tag number was--
...وفقما أذكر، كان رقم بطاقة ذاك الرجل
Number 98.
رقم 98
Which means the other person in the deal
ما يعني أنّ طرف الصفقة الآخر
cut in between the old man and Ran!
دخل بين العمّ وران
It was those three!
!أحد أولئك الثلاثة
That big man exchanged tags, and completed the deal.
بادل ذاك الرجل العملاق البطاقة، وتمّت الصفقة
And then the instant he opened the briefcase to check its contents...
...وعندما فتح الحقيبة لتفقّد محتواها
Wait.
لحظة
If the goal was to kill him from the very start,
إن كان هدفه قتل الرجل العملاق من البداية
why did they choose this place to make the deal?
لمَ اختار القاتل أن يعقد الصفقة في مكان كهذا؟
If an incident happens at your own trade show,
...إذا وقعت حادثة في معرض إعلان شركتك
you could make yourself suspect if you're not careful.
قد تقع في الشبهة إلم تكون حذراً
Yet they knew for a fact that he would check the briefcase...
...كان يعلم أنّ الرجل العملاق سيتفقد الحقيبة
And the fact that the key doesn't match the briefcase bothers me.
كما عدم مطابقة المفتاح للحقيبة تحيّرني
Wait! Could I have made a really big mistake!
!لحظة... أيمكن أنّي ارتكبتُ خطأً كبيراً؟
Number 38.
رقم 38
Number 56.
رقم 56
Looks like nobody knew who that large man was...
يبدو أنّ لا أحد يعرف من كان الرجل العملاق
Nope. And nobody saw anybody suspicious, either.
أجل، ولم ير أحد شخصاً مثيراً للشبهة أيضاً
Number 99, right?
رقم 99، صحيح؟
Yes!
!أجل
Number 97.
رقم 97
Here.
هاك
Number 124.
رقم 124
What?
ماذا؟
No, nothing.
كلا، لا شيء
Hey, you guys should check your briefcases.
يجدر بكما التحقّق من حقيبتيكما أيضاً
They all look the same, after all.
فجميعها تبدو متشابهة
No, that's alright.
كلا، لا داعي
There's nothing important inside, anyway.
فلا شيء مهم في الداخل
Wait a minute! Could this be... Now I see! So that's how it was!
...لحظة! أيمكن، أيمكن
In the eyes of the killer, this was an unexpected murder!
!كانت هذه جريمة غير متوقّعة بالنسبة للقاتل
Alright, folks.
حسناً يا جماعة
You can go home for today,
يمكنكم الرجوع لليوم
but if anyone recalls seeing someone
لكن إذا تذكّر أحدكم رؤية
who might have been the bomber,
شخص مثير للشبهة يمكن أنّه كان المُفجّر
please contact me at the police headquarters!
اتّصلوا بي في مركز الشرطة رجاءً
This is bad!
هذا سيّئ
If they let everyone leave now, we'll never know who did it!
إذا غادر الجميع الآن فلن نعرف !من كان الفاعل أبداً
Darn it!
...تبّاً
I have an idea who the bomber might be,
...لديّ فكرة عن المُفجّر
but I'm still not sure!
!لكنّي لست متيقناً بعد
I have no choice.
لا خيار أمامي
I'll have to use the old man's voice and body
عليّ استعمال صوت وجسد العمّ
to lay a trap!
!ونصب فخّ للفاعل
It hit Ran in the butt!
!أصبت مؤخرة ران
Are you alright, Dad?
أأنت بخير يا أبي؟
Hey. Do you still got my number tag?
لا تزالين تملكين بطاقة رقمي؟
Why isn't Ran getting sleepy?
لمَ لم يصب ران النعاس؟
Don't worry, I have it here in my pocket.
لا تقلق، إنّها هنا في جيبي
Oh, it hit the tag...
...أصبت البطاقة إذاً
But I only have one sleeping dart!
!لكن لديّ سهم واحد منوّم الآن
Let's get our stuff and go home already...
لنأخذ أغراضنا ونرجع بسرعة
Alright.
حسناً
Pervert!
!ماذا تفعل أيّها المنحرف
Don't tell me that was you...
أكان ذلك أنت يا كونان-كن؟
It was lint! There was some lint on your bottom, so--
...كـ-كانت قمامة! التصق بعضها بمؤخرتك
You really should put your leg down now...
...عليك إنزال ساقك الآن
Dad!
!أ-أبي
Are you alright?!
أأنت بخير يا أبي؟
I'm fine, Ran.
أنا بخير يا ران
You just helped me realize something.
ساعدتِني في إدراك شيء
Realize something?
إدراك شيء؟
Inspector Megure.
مفتّش ميغوري
You can't let the people leave just yet.
لا يمكنك ترك الزوّار يغادرون بعد
You can't be serious!
!لا تكن سخيفاً
We're dealing with a random bomber!
!نحن نتعامل مع مُفجّر عشوائي
There could be more bombs!
!هناك احتمال بوجود المزيد من القنابل
A random bomber?
مُفجّر عشوائي؟
There were never any bombs planted in this hotel.
لم تكن هناك أيّ قنابل مزروعة في هذا الفندق من البداية
That bomb was planted in that man's belongings
وُضعت تلك القنبلة في أمتعة ذاك الرجل
in order to specifically kill him.
لقتله تحديداً
Do you wish to let them go,
أتنوي حقّاً السماح لهم بالمغادرة
even though the bomber is among them?
مع أنّ القاتل بينهم؟
What? You know who did it?!
!ماذا؟ عرفت هويّته؟
If we check the contents of something,
إذا تفقدنا محتويات شيءٍ ما
the person responsible will admit to doing it.
سيعترف الفاعل بارتكابه للجريمة
The contents of what?
محتويات شيء ما؟
That would be--
...ذلك
Nakajima-san.
ناكاجيما-سان
The contents of that briefcase you've been holding so importantly!
محتويات الحقيبة التي تتمسك بها بكلّ اهتمام لفترة
Let us see what's inside.
دعنا نتفقّد ما داخلها
No, you can't!
!لا-لا يمكنكم
You idiot! Do you want to look like the murderer?!
!أحمق! أتريد أن تبدو القاتل؟
Show them!
!أرهم
Let go!
!د-دعني
Stop!
!توقّف
Takeshita!
!تـ-تاكيشيتا
Now there's no doubt about it.
لا شكّ الآن
Takeshita-san. You're the bomber.
تاكيشيتا-سان، أنت المُفجّر
How so, Mori-kun?!
كيف ذلك يا موري-كن؟
Because he thought the bomb he put in the briefcase would explode.
لأنّه ظنّ أن القنبلة التي وضعها في الحقيبة ستنفجر
A bomb inside the briefcase?!
قـ-قنبلة داخل الحقيبة؟
Indeed.
أجل
The briefcase emblem found at the scene of the explosion
شعار الحقيبة التي وجدناه في مسرح الجريمة
was bent away from the case.
كان مثنياً للخارج
In other words, it received a shock from the inside.
أي أنّه تلقى صدمة من الداخل
Meaning that the bomb was inside the briefcase.
فالقنبلة كانت داخل الحقيبة
Wait. Then when he said,
...لحظة، عندما قال الرجل العملاق إذاً
"Huh? It won't open. Is this empty?" he meant--
..."ماذا؟ لا يفتح. لحظة، مفتوحة بالفعل؟"
That's right.
أجل
The key wouldn't open the briefcase.
ما كان المفتاح ليفتح الحقيبة
And it was the briefcase's cover that was empty.
وقد كان غطاء الحقيبة ما كان مفتوحاً
So he gave that briefcase bomb to that large man?
أي أنّه أعطى الحقيبة المفخّخة للرجل العملاق؟
No.
كلا
The person the victim was making a deal with gave him the briefcase...
الشخص الذي أعطى الرجل العملاق الحقيبة ...ومن عقد صفقةً معه
...you, Nakajima-san!
!كانت أنت يا ناكاجيما-سان
The deal was done by having everyone temporarily check their bags in
تمّت الصفقة بإيداع الحقيبتين مؤقتاً في مكتب الإيداع
and then exchanging number tags afterward.
ثمّ تبادل بطاقات الأرقام لاحقاً
As proof of this,
ودليلاً على ذلك
I got ♪96 and my daughter Ran got ♪100.
كان رقم بطاقتي 96، وبطاقة ابنتي ران 100
But Ueda-san, Nakajima-san, and Takeshita-san
دخل أويدا-سان وناكاجيما-سان وتاكيشيتا-سان
cut in between us.
الثلاثة بيننا
Naturally, their tag numbers would have been 97, 98, and 99.
فمن الطبيعيّ أن تكون أرقام بطاقاتهم هي 97 و98 و99
But for some reason,
لكن لسببٍ ما
when Nakajima-san went to claim his briefcase,
عندما ذهب ناكاجيما-سان لاستلام حقيبته
his tag was--
...كان رقم بطاقته
Number 124.
هو 124
And then the tag of the large man Conan overheard was--
ثمّ رقم بطاقة الرجل العملاق ...الذي سمعه كونان
Number 98.
هو 98
The tags were probably exchanged
تمّ تبادل البطاقتين
when Nakajima-san and Conan bumped into the man.
عندما ارتطم ناكاجيما-سان مع كونان بالرجل العملاق لاحقاً
The man then took Nakajima-san's briefcase from the baggage counter.
أخذ الرجل حقيبة ناكاجيما-سان من مكتب الإيداع
The instant he checked the contents while inside the restroom--
...وذهب لتفقّد محتواها في دورة المياه، وعندها
But why didn't the key fit?
لـ-لكن لمَ لم يدخل المفتاح؟
Of course it wouldn't fit.
لا عجب
Takeshita-san had switched that briefcase in advance.
فتاكيشيتا-سان قد بدّل الحقيبتين سلفاً
Yes.
أجل
Because Takeshita-san had meant for that briefcase bomb
لأنّ تاكيشيتا-سان خطّط بالحقيبة المفخّخة
to kill Nakajima-san!
أن يقتل ناكاجيما-سان
What?!
!ماذا؟
Your number tags were probably switched
استبدلت البطاقتين عندما جعلت
when you had Nakajima-san play that punching game.
ناكاجيما-سان يلعب لعبة الملاكمة غالباً
But when Takeshita-san checked the briefcase bomb in,
،لكن عندما أراد تاكيشيتا-سان إيداع الحقيبة المفخخة
a dangerous problem arose.
ظهرت مشكلة مزعجة
My baggage tag number was 96.
كان رقم بطاقتي 96
Nakajima-san was close behind me,
كان ناكاجيما-سان قريباً ورائي
so it was certain that he would be in the 90's too.
فكان مؤكداً أنّ رقمه سيكون في التسعينات أيضاً
But Takeshita-san hadn't gotten in line yet,
لكنّ تاكيشيتا-سان لم يدخل الصفّ بعدها وقتها
so he would be in the 100's.
فكان رقمه سيكون في المئات
There was a good chance Nakajima-san might notice later
كان الاحتمال كبيراً أن يلاحظ ناكاجيما-سان لاحقاً
if he switched their two numbers.
إذا بدّل رقميهما لاحقاً
That's why Takeshita-san cut in between me and Ran...
لذا قطع تاكيشيتا-سان ...الصفّ بيني وران
To ensure his tag number would be in the 90's,
كي يكون رقم بطاقته في التسعينات
the same as Nakajima-san's!
مثل ناكاجيما-سان
But is there any proof?
لكن أهناك دليل؟
Yes...
أجل
The briefcase Takeshita-san has right now
الحقيبة التي يحملها تاكيشيتا-سان الآن
is the one Nakajima-san was supposed to give the large man.
هي التي كان يُفترض أن يسلّمها ناكاجيما-سان للرجل العملاق
The key found at the scene of the explosion
المفتاح الذي وجدناه في مسرح الانفجار
should fit it perfectly.
سيدخل بلا مشاكل
And it was a Mantendo original briefcase that exploded.
كما ما انفجر كانت حقيبة أصلية تابعة لشركة مانتيندو
It should be obvious once you inspect all the briefcases
يُفترض أن يكون الأمر جليّاً بعد تفتيش كلّ الحقائب
belonging to Mantendo employees here today
التي تخصّ موظّفي مانتيندو هنا اليوم
that Takeshita-san's is the only one missing.
سيتّضح أن حقيبة تاكيشيتا-سان هي الوحيدة المفقودة
Because his briefcase was blown to pieces.
فقد تفجّرت لأشلاء سلفاً
To think that explosion was from a bomb I set...
من كان ليتصوّر أن الانفجار من القنبلة التي جهّزتُها أنا
I even wrote a threatening letter
أرسلتُ رسالة تهديد حتّى
to make it look like an act of terrorism.
كي أجعله يبدو عملاً إرهابياً
Boy, is my face red!
...لكن كيف انقلبت الأمور
Takeshita!
!تاكيشيتا
That's right! You were supposed to die!
!صحيح! كان يُفترض أن تكون أنت من يموت
You murdered Yoshimi!
!قتلتَ يوشيمي
Yoshimi?
يوشيمي؟
The manager of our boxing team during our college days.
مديرة فريق الملاكمة من أيامنا في الجامعة
She committed suicide after Nakajima dumped her.
أقدمت على الانتحار بعدما هجرها ناكاجيما
Suicide?
الانتحار؟
Yoshimi had been very close friends with Takeshita
كانت يوشيمي تواعد تاكيشيتا
ever since middle school.
منذ المرحلة الإعدادية
So he must have been--
...لذا قام غالباً
Let me go! I'm innocent! He did it!
!دعوني! أنا بريء! هو الفاعل
You narrowly avoided being murdered, Nakajima-san.
بالكاد تفاديت مقتلك يا ناكاجيما-سان
But what do you say we move on to the real issue here?
هلّا انتقلنا للمشكلة الرئيسية؟
The man in black you were making a deal with...
الرجل بالرداء الأسود الذي عقدت صفقة معه
Who exactly was he?!
من كان بالضبط؟
Um...
...فـ-في الواقع
You've ruined the deal--
...أفسدتَ الصفقة
their organization is going to come after you, no matter what.
فستلاحقك منظمتهم بنهاية المطاف
Organization?!
منظمتهم؟
I think your wisest choice would be to tell us everything
الخيار الحكيم هو الإفصاح لنا عن كلّ شيء
and seek police shelter...
وطلب حماية الشرطة
I really don't know anything!
!لا-لا أعرف شيئاً حقاً
Just that the place I met them at was always the same.
فقط أنّ المكان الذي ألتقيهم فيه كان نفسه دوماً
A bar named "Cocktail," on the top floor of the Daikoku Building...
...حانة تُدعى "كوكتيل" في الطابق الأعلى لبناية دايكوكو
"Cocktail," at the Daikoku Building!
كوكتيل" في بناية دايكوكو؟"
Hey, Mori-kun! What organization are you talking about?!
!موري-كن! أيّ منظمة تقصد؟
Hey!
!أخبرني
Daikoku Building
بناية دايكوكو
So this is the place!
!هذا المكان إذاً
I made it!
!وصلت
I finally found them!
وجدتهم أخيراً
I finally made it here!
!وصلت هنا
What?!
!ماذا؟
Damn it!
!تبّاً
Stay out of there, little boy!
!كلا يا صبيّ! ابتعد من هنا
Let go! I'm not a little boy!
!دعني! لستُ صبيّاً
I'm... I'm...
...أنا... أنا
Let go!
!دعني
According to police investigation afterward,
وفق تحقيقات الشرطة لاحقاً
the amount of explosives used was incredible,
كانت كميّة المتفجرات المستعملة هائلة
and the bar was completely obliterated.
ونُسفت الحانة بالكامل
There was no way to tell if anybody had been inside.
لم تكن هناك طريقة لمعرفة ما إن كان هناك أحد في الداخل
All that I found out this time
كلّ ما اكتشفتُه هذه المرّة
was that the men in black were attempting to purchase
أنّ الرجال بالرداء الأسود كانوا يحاولون شراء
a list of the world's top programmers
لائحة لنخبة مُبرمجي العالم
that Nakajima-san had smuggled out of the company.
قام بتسريبها ناكاجيما-سان من الشركة
Are Gin and Vodka dead?
هل مات جين وفودكا؟
Or did they disappear on their own?
أم اختفيا بنفسيهما؟
Everything remains a mystery.
يبقى كلّ شيء لغزاً
Just as the black smoke covers the sky...
كما غطّى الدخان السماء
...so too is the case buried in darkness.
غطّى الظلام القضيّة
Hey, Mister! Your button's about to fall off!
انتبه يا عمّ، يكاد زرّك أن يسقط
This was neither an accident nor a suicide!
!لم تكن حادثة أو انتحاراً
It was a homicide! A murder!
!بل جريمة! جريمة قتل
Why, you...
!أنت
You're in the way! Go outside!
!إنّك عقبة! اخرج
That's it! Now I understand Dr. Date's train trick!
!فهمتها الآن! حيلة القطار للطبيب داتي
The Train Trick Murder Case
جريمة قتل حيلة القطار
On the next Conan--
في الحلقة القادمة من كونان
Next Conan's Hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
Snack Cart Sales.
مبيعات عربة طعام
Next episode features an authentic mystery.
الحلقة القادمة تحوي !استنتاجات جادة مجدّداً
Would you like some tea or sandwiches?
أيريد أحد علبة طعام أم شاي أم ساندوتش؟